Guide to the Women's Network Records, 1975-1988 UA.28.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Women's Network records
1975-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Women's Network
UA.28.01.0001
3 Linear Feet
The Women's Network began in 1975 when female faculty began meeting in a caucus to discuss issues surrounding "the recruitment, retention, and treatment of faculty women." Later on its focus expanded to include matters of sexual harassment, salary equity, and the dual responsibilities of work and family. The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, committee minutes, flyers, reports, clippings, and other materials form the faculty and the staff/administrative divisions of the Women's Network.
2,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Women's Network Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1985-1987.
Historical Note
Female faculty began meeting in a caucus in 1975. A formal organizational plan was drawn up and approved in March of 1979. The Women's Network was originally concerned with issues surrounding "the recruitment, retention, and treatment of faculty women." Its focus later expanded to include matters of sex discrimination, sexual harassment, salary equity, the dual responsibilities of work and family, and other matters. In the early 1980's, the Women's Network separated into two distinct divisions, one for faculty, and one for staff and administrators. Members of the Women's Network also assisted in setting up a network for graduate and professional women students.
Collection Overview
The collection includes correspondence, memoranda, committee minutes, flyers, reports, clippings, and other materials form the faculty (committee A) and the staff/administrative (committee B) divisions of the Women's Network. Subjects include parental leave, tenure, recruitment and hiring, salary equity, sexual harassment and TIAA-CREF matters. There is one sealed envelope containing records of a sexual harassment case. It has been removed from the collection and placed in the vault; it will remain closed until 2037.
Separated Material
One sealed envelope containing records of a sexual harassment case has been removed from the collection and placed in the vault; it is closed until 2037.
Related Material
Women’s Center records, 1984-2002.
University Archives, Duke University.
Women college teachers -- North Carolina -- Durham; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Salaries, etc.; Sexual harassment of women -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Sex discrimination in higher education -- United States; Sex discrimination in employment -- United States; Pay equity; Discrimination in employment -- Law and legislation -- United States; Women in higher education -- North Carolina -- Durham; Women college administrators -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Women's Network
- Minutes, 1977-1979, 25 folders
  - Meeting Announcements/Minutes, 1977-1978 (1) (Box 1)
  - Meeting Announcements/Minutes, 1977-1978 (2) (Box 1)
  - August 31, 1978 Meeting (Box 1)
  - September 27, 1978 Meeting (1) (Box 1)
  - September 27, 1978 Meeting (2) (Box 1)
  - November 9, 1978 Meeting (Box 1)
  - December 7, 1978 Meeting (Box 1)
  - December, 1978 Update (Box 1)
  - January 19, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - January 29, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - February 14, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - February 21, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - February 28, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - March 7, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - May 10, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - July 12, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - September 12, 1979 Party (Box 1)
  - September 24, 1979 Meeting (1) (Box 1)
  - September 24, 1979 Meeting (2) (Box 1)
  - October 9, 1979 Meeting (1) (Box 1)
  - October 9, 1979 Meeting (2) (Box 1)
  - October 24, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - November 8, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - December 11, 1979 Meeting (Box 1)
  - December 19, 1979 Party (Box 1)
- HERS (Higher Education Resource Services) Workshop, 1979, 10 folders
  - HERS Workshop Group Assignments, 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Materials (1), 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Materials (2), 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Materials, Addendum to, 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Participants, 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Pre-Registration, 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Questionnaire (1), 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Questionnaire (2), 1980 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Schedule, 1979 (Box 1)
  - HERS Workshop Statistical Information, 1979 (Box 1)
- Subject files,1975-1988, 2 boxes
  - Affirmative Action Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report on Equal Opportunity and Affirmative Action, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Duke Affirmative Action Material, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Equal Opportunity and Affirmative Action, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - 1979-1981 Records (1) (Box 1)
  - 1979-1981 Records (2) (Box 1)
  - General, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - General, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Anthropology Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - Chronicle (Ruby), 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Duke Benefits, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Endorsements of Original Letter, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Goldhor, Susan - How to Keep a Job/How to Get a Job, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Guidelines, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Harassment Materials, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Interviewing Candidates, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Materials, Spring 1979 (Box 1)
  - Materials, Summer 1979 (Box 1)
  - National Science Foundation/Women in Science Projects, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Network Article (Box 1)
  - Network Directory (Box 1)
  - Part-time and Visiting Appointments, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Retention, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Smeal, Eleanor Cutri, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Sociology Department, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Survey Results, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Tables, Articles and Statistics, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Title IX Material, 1979 (Box 1)
  - UNC-Chapel Hill Salary Study. 1979 (Box 1)
  - Wardropper Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Women in Medicine Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Young Letter and Endorsements, 1979 (Box 1)
  - [Addition] Records, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
  - Add-On Policy, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Administrative Searches, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Committee A, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - Committee B, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
  - General (1), 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - General (2), 1977-1978 (Box 2)
  - General (3), 1979 (Box 2)
  - Non-Regular Faculty, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Parenting Leave, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment and Hiring (1), 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment and Hiring (2), 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment and Hiring (3), 1978-1987 (Box 2)
  - Recruitment and Hiring (4), 1978-1987 (Box 2)
  - Retirement - TIAA-CREF, 1976-1981 (Box 2)
  - Salary Equity, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
  - Sexual Harassment, 1980-1987 (Box 2)
  - Steering Committee, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Tenure and Retention of Female Faculty (Box 2)